<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <a name="profiles_active"> </a>
  <h3>List of active profiles</h3>
  <p>This page contains a list with the name and a short description for all the active profiles, that are defined in this IG. </p>

  <!-- A -->
  <p><b>A</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Attachment-IEHR.html">Attachment - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the Attachment resource when it is used in a DocumentReference-MedicalDocument resource. <br/>
    </li>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-AuditEvent-IEHR.html">AuditEvent - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the AuditEvent StructureDefinition and makes the agent performing the audit and the time it was perfomed mandatory.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- B -->
  <p><b>B</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Observation-BioSignal-IEHR.html">BioSignal - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Observation StructureDefinition and represents a BioSignal. Since a BioSignal may contain more than one value, the actual values of the BioSignal are included as components (Observation.component).
    </li>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Bundle-IEHR.html">Bundle - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Bundle StructureDefinition and adds a constraint, that makes the Signature mandatory, if the bundle has the type document.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- C -->
  <p><b>C</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Condition-IEHR.html">Condition - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Condition resource and constraints the code to be an ICD-10 code.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Composition-IEHR.html">Composition - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the ClinicalDocument StructureDefinition and constrains extensions that allow to add a signature to the Composition and its own confidentiality code to each section.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Composition-IPS-IEHR.html">Composition - IPS - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Composition-IPS StructureDefinition and further constrains the result-section to avoid a potential error when referencing Observation-results.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Consent-IEHR.html">Consent - IEHR</a>  <br/>
      This profile is based on the Consent resource and defines multiple mandatory attributes to ensure the accountability of a Patient's agreement to an attached structured Consent document.
    </li>

    <li>  <a href="StructureDefinition-ConsentApproval-IEHR.html">Consent - IEHR</a>
      <br/>
      This profile is based on the Provenance resource and constrains the Provenance's agent to be of type author, the target to reference a Consent-IEHR and the mandatory signature to be of type ConsentSignature-IEHR.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- D -->
  <p><b>D</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticConclusion-IEHR.html">DiagnosticConclusion - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based in the Condition StructureDefinition and further constrains the code and note attributes to allow the addition of unstructured data to a CarePlan (TreatmentPlan-IEHR) in the form of free text.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticReport-BioSignalReport-IEHR.html">DiagnosticReport BioSignalReport - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DiagnosticReport when it represents findings of Instrumental Examination in the context of the CBDE.
      It can be used to represent a BioSignal as well as single images, e.g EKG readouts, or complete ImagingStudies.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticReport-IEHR.html">DiagnosticReport - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to a general DiagnosticReport in the context of the CBDE.
      The different types of reports in the CBDE context are derived from it.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticReport-ImagingReport-IEHR.html">DiagnosticReport Imaging - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DiagnosticReport when it represents radiology findings in the context of the CBDE.
      It is used to document the diagnostics generated from the results of imaging observations and the informations surrounding them.
      It can be used to either represent single images, e.g EKG readouts, or complete ImagingStudies.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticReport-LaboratoryReport-IEHR.html">DiagnosticReport LaboratoryResult - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DiagnosticReport when it represents laboratory findings in the context of the CBDE.
      It is used to document the diagnostics generated from the results of laboratory observations and the informations surrounding them.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DiagnosticReport-VitalSignReport-IEHR.html">DiagnosticReport VitalSignReport - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DiagnosticReport when it represents vital signs in the context of CBDE.
      It is used to document diagnoses generated from results of vital sign surveys and the information accompanying them.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DocumentManifest-IEHR.html">DocumentManifest-IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DocumentManifest resource when it is used in the context of the CBDE.
      It is used to represent a collection of unstructured documents, that can then be exchanged.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-DocumentReference-IEHR.html">DocumentReference - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the DocumentReference resource when it represents medicaldocuments in the context of the CBDE.
      It is used to represent unstructered documents as structured resources, that can then be exchanged.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- E -->
  <p><b>E</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Encounter-IEHR.html">Encounter - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the Encounter resource, when it represents a visit in the context of the CBDE.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- F -->
  <p><b>F</b><br/>
  <!-- G -->
  <b>G</b></p>

  <!-- H -->
  <p><b>H</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Composition-HospitalDischargeReport-IEHR.html">HospitalDischargeReport - IEHR</a> <br/>
      This profile is based on the Composition-IEHR StructureDefinition and defines the relevant sections to represent a DischargeReport.
      The sections contained are based on the table in the IEHR-Profiles-requirements mapping document and are not necessarily final.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- I -->
  <p><b>I</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li>><a href="StructureDefinition-Immunization-IEHR.html">Immunization - IEHR</a><br/>
    This profile is based on the Immunization-IPS StructuredDefinition and changes the preferred vaccineCode to an ATC code.</li>
  </ul>

  <!-- J -->
  <p><b>J</b><br/>
  <!-- K -->
  <b>K</b><br/>
  <!-- L -->
  <b>L</b><br/>
  <!-- M -->
  <b>M</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Media-IEHR.html">Media - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Media StructureDefinition and adds a mandatory signature.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Composition-VisitReport-IEHR.html">MedicalVisit - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Composition-IEHR StructureDefinition and defines the relevant sections to represent a VisitReport.
      The sections contained are based on the table in the IEHR-Profiles-requirements mapping document and are not necessarily final.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Medication-IEHR.html">Medication - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ips/StructureDefinition/Medication-uv-ips">MedicationIPS</a> profile and constraints the Medication.code to be an ATC code.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-MedicationRequest-prescription-IEHR.html">MedicationRequest-Prescription - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the MedicationRequest in the context of the CBDE.
      It is used to document the prescription of different medications in clinical contexts, e.g. CarePlans or hospital visits.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-MedicationStatement-IEHR.html">MedicationStatement - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/ips/StructureDefinition/MedicationStatement-uv-ips">MedicationStatementIPS</a> profile and constraints the MedicationStatement.medication to reference a Medication-IEHR.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- N -->
  <b>N</b>
  <!-- O -->
  <p><b>O</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Observation-IEHR.html">Observation - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile constraints the codes used in Observation.code to be LOINC codes.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- P -->
  <p><b>P</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Patient-IEHR.html">Patient - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the Patient StructureDefinition in the context of the CBDE.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Period-IEHR.html">Period - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the Period Datatype in the context of the CBDE. It is used to ensure the documentation of a start time.
    </li>

    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Provenance-IEHR.html">Provenance - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile represents the constraints applied to the Provenance StructureDefinition in the contextof the CBDE. This includes the mandatory agents Author and Provider, as well as a mandatory signature.
      A Provenance may be referenced by the direct children of the Provenance's target.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- Q -->
  <p><b>Q</b><br/>
  <!-- R -->
  <b>R</b></p>

  <!-- S -->
  <p><b>S</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-Provenance-Signature-IEHR.html">Provenance-Signature - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the Signature StructureDefinition and defines the constraints applied to the resource when it is used in the context of the CBDE.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- T -->
  <p><b>T</b></p>
  <ul>
    <li><a href="StructureDefinition-TreatmentPlan-IEHR.html">TreatmentPlan - IEHR</a><br/>
      This profile is based on the CarePlan StructureDefinition and defines a TreatmentPlan, that uses the CarePlan.description attribute to describe the required activities.
    </li>
  </ul>

  <!-- U -->
  <p><b>U</b><br/>
  <!-- V -->
  <b>V</b><br/>
  <!-- W -->
  <b>W</b><br/>
  <!-- X -->
  <b>X</b><br/>
  <!-- Y -->
  <b>Y</b><br/>
  <!-- Z -->
  <b>Z</b></p>

</div>
