<div align="justify" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <p>
    <b>Translation in a nutshell:</b> The different translations of a resource should be contained in a single resource and use extensions.
  </p>
  <a name="original"> </a>
  <h3>Original language</h3>
  <p>
    The language attribute of the resource (Resource.language) contains the language in which it was created originally created and all attributes contain the original text in this language.
  </p>

  <a name="translation"> </a>
  <h3>Translation</h3>
  <p>
    To translate a text attribute it is extended with the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/translation">Translation Extension</a>.
    This extension contains a language (Extension.lang) and the translated text (Extension.content). Therefor, the to-be-translated attribute should have one extension for each different language.</p>

  <p>
    Information about the system or person providing the translation can be provided by extending the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/translation">Translation Extension</a> with the <a href="StructureDefinition-ExtendedTranslation-IEHR.html">ExtendedTranslation-IEHR Extension</a>.
    The ExtendedTranslation-IEHR contains a reference to a <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/Provenance">Provenance</a> resource with relevant information about the translation process, like the actor and the time of translation.
    This provenance should be transmitted together with the resources, but if multiple resources were translated together they can reference the same provenance.
    Thus, if for each language all resources are translated together into that language, it should be sufficient to have one provenance for each language.
    All translations in the same language would also reference the same Provenance in the ExtendedTranslation-IEHR, too.
  </p>
</div>
